MARIAM MOHAMED

Minneapolis MN

Phone: 612-715-8584 | Email: MariamSMohamed22@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mariam-mohamed-616303246 GitHub: www.github.com/Mimimoha

SUMMARY

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player, excellent communicator and a persistent problem solver. Offering 4 years of exceptional technical skills and related experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJs, NodeJs, API, JSON, Responsive Design, PWA, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL.

Tools: Git, Slack, Azure, Figma, VScode, Trello, Railway, Insomnia, Heroku

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Analyst Mosaic Health Services

2022-Present Minneapolis,MN

- Performed user account maintenance tasks, assigning new credentials, archiving defunct credentials and monitoring login system for suspicious trends.
- Created Customized development frameworks for customers based on specific business goals and budgetary constraints.
- Designed and integrated software solutions based on business requirements and objectives.

Key Accomplishments:

- Effectively added over 200 employees and client login credentials.
- Successfully worked in a team to add over 10 different features to existing employee portal.

IT Help Desk Technician Minneapolis Public Housing Authority

2020-2022

Minneapolis, MN

- Installed, Modified and repaired software and hardware to resolve technical issues.
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Transferred all tenant and owner data to a new software, and worked closely with software developers to debug any issues.

Key Accomplishments:

- Closed over 200 tickets weekly, reassigned over 400 tickets to appropriate employees.
- Successfully helped the agency transfer to a remote work in weeks notice due to the pandemic.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Housing Inspector Minneapolis Public Housing Authority

2018-2020

- Minneapolis, MN
- Conducted annually, initial and special inspections.
- Worked with owners/tenants to schedule and address any HQS violations.
- Performed routine agency vehicle maintenance.

Key Accomplishment:

- Eared HQS Specialist Certifications within the first week of employment.
- Effectively assisted co-workers with setting up new lpads and Thinkpads for remote work.

PROJECTS

MMHD https://github.com/hoffh-5334/propertyManager

MMHD Residences Property Management is an apartment complex offering luxury units and a quality management team. The website features both restricted and unrestricted content.

-Tech Stack: MySQL, Sequelize, Connect-session-sequelize, Express Handlebars, Express-sessions, bcrypt, Slick- Carousel, Slack, Figma, Trello.

Catify https://github.com/wlk-dev/catify https://wlk-dev.github.io/catify/

Catify is a fun tool that gathers data from numerous APIs and provides users with predictions of their age, gender and nationalization. Catify will also present users with the most compatible cat breed.

-Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Coloris, Swiper, Third Party APIs, Figma, Slack, Trello.

MACDEV https://github.com/Mimimoha/machdev https://machdev.herokuapp.com/

Macdev is a web application that provides a way to dynamically generate a company website information using stored data in a MongoDB. Application is generated by passing data from a fetch request as a prop to generate in corresponding pages.

-Tech Stack: MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Semantic UI ReactJS, Semantic UI Bootstrap, Heroku, Github, Figma, Slack, Trello.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: U of M
Housing Quality Standards Certificate: Nan Mckay

Bachelors of Science Management: Saint Cloud State University

Minneapolis, MN
St.Cloud, MN